This suit looks good, doesn't it?
這件西裝不錯吧
It is what I just bought.
是新買的
The shirt and tie as well.
襯衫跟領結也是
By the way, let us take a photo as a memento first.
對了 先拍照留念吧
Please get to the point.
麻煩您有話快說
Even though I have guessed it.
雖然我大致猜到了
Nothing, actually I have a headache.
沒有啦 實際上我很頭疼
The recent bombing attack has heightened public hostility toward the Republic.
由於上次的爆炸恐襲 導致社會對共和國的觀感越來越差
BREAKING NEWS: UNUSUAL EXPLOSION AT THE MAGIC BUREAU
(快訊 魔導廳離奇爆炸)
I can't stand it.
真受不了
I have only recently begun encouraging both sides to engage in peaceful dialogue.
才正開始著手促進雙方和平交流
Peaceful dialogue has been a pipe dream from the start.
打從一開始 和平交流就是天方夜譚
The Kingdom will never recognize the Republic's claims or territories.
王國不可能認同 共和國的主張或占有領土
What should we do then, Fred?
那要怎麼辦嘛 小弗雷德
Doesn't this imply that the Kingdom and the Republic will go to war?
王國或共和國不就會 正式展開武力衝突嗎
But after all, the Republic has Leo.
不過說到底 共和國有雷奧在
We can't defeat them with ordinary means as long as he is in the Republic.
只要他還在 根本無法用普通的手段攻下那裡
As long as Leo…
一旦雷奧…
As long as Leo what?
一旦雷奧什麼
As long as Leo is gone, the Republic has no way to stop itself from falling apart.
一旦雷奧消失 共和國將會無能為力 分崩離析
Yeah.
是啊
It is unfortunate, but now that the situation has reached this point,
雖然很遺憾 但是事已至此
we must ask Leo to accept responsibility and disappear.
只好請雷奧負起責任 消失無蹤
But only you, the hero's companion, are capable of doing so.
但只有同為勇者夥伴的你們辦得到
Max is no longer of any use.
麥克斯已經派不上用場
HERO MAX HAVE TEN LOVERS AT THE SAME TIME
(勇者麥克斯 腳踏十條船)
Yuria has retired too.
尤莉亞也引退了
I can handle Leo alone.
雷奧那種貨色 我獨自對付就夠了
In the past,
以前啊
even someone like me had a so-called best friend.
就連我這種人 也有所謂的摯友
He was my classmate in school, and we both joined the Magic Bureau at the same time.
是學生時代的同學 在魔導廳也是同期
He had better grades than me.
他的成績比我優異
He was increasingly successful.
越來越飛黃騰達
But one day, I found evidence of his corruption.
卻在某天發現了他行事不當的證據
So I made it public.
我便將這件事公諸於世
Of course, he lost his footing and fell apart.
他當然因此失去立足之地 一蹶不振
Then you replaced that friend and got promoted all the way.
然後您就代替那位摯友一路升官
You really know how to mock people, Fred.
真會挖苦人 小弗雷德
But…
不過…
Now I'm completely an old man.
如果是徹底變成大叔的現在
I would probably solve things like that privately.
八成會暗中解決那種事
That being said,
話雖如此
I don't think what I did then was wrong.
我並不認為我當時的做法是錯的
He took the wrong path.
是他誤入歧途
So I corrected it.
而我出手矯正
That incident hurt me deeply.
令我痛徹心扉
I still dream about it occasionally.
現在偶爾還會夢見
Don't joke with me.
別開玩笑了
Do you think I will suffer as a result of cleaning up after that filthy terrorist?
莫非您認為我會為了 收拾那個骯髒恐怖分子而痛苦嗎
Impossible.
那怎麼可能
I will go alone.
我會獨自前往
You don't need to persuade me.
不需要您來說服我
Thank you.
謝謝
You must come back alive.
一定要活著回來喔
Not bad at all.
真不錯
This man has truly won my heart.
這男人深得我心
Fred.
小弗雷德
(Level 1 Demon Lord and One Room Hero)
《LV1魔王與獨居廢勇者》
(Episode 9: The Hero's Tangle)
(#9 勇者的糾結)
Your Majesty,
陛下
Regarding the analysis of that thing,
關於那個東西的分析結果
I hope you can give me a little more time.
希望陛下再給屬下一點時間
Okay.
嗯
Let's just leave it at that. It's a unique situation.
先這樣吧 畢竟現在情況特殊
Max.
麥克斯
You really had a hard time yesterday.
昨天真是辛苦了
Is your stomach feeling any better?
肚子有沒有好一點
Max, I didn't know you were so distressed.
麥克斯 朕都不知道你是如此苦惱
You even cried so hard.
居然哭成這樣
BOAT RACE
(競艇)
What's going on with this?
這畫面是怎麼回事
SINGLE BET ON TANAKA PLAYER, 89 000 YEN Did you cry because you lost the bet?
(單押 塔納卡選手 89000日圓) 難道你是賭輸了才嚎啕大哭
What's wrong with you?
搞什麼啦
WE'RE SORRY THAT YOU DIDN'T WIN, NO REFUNDS Who bets this way, are you stupid?
(十分遺憾 沒中 恕不退費) 而且哪有人這樣下注 白痴嗎
A jobless person risks 90 000 on a boat race.
一個無業遊民還敢砸九萬賭競艇
Because… if I win, I can get 40 times the amount.
因為…中了就能贏40倍
You'd better win.
最好會中啦
I got it, next time I'll place a safer bet.
知道了啦 下次選穩一點的下注
Give me some pocket money.
給我零用錢
I can only give you 50 000.
只給五萬喔
Your Majesty,
陛下
we don't have time to gamble now.
現在沒有時間賭博
Please take a look at the television.
快看電視
EMERGENCY PRESS CONFERENCE BY THE BESKER KINGDOM GOVERNMENT The kingdom is adamant about not giving in to terrorists.
(貝斯卡王國政府緊急召開記者會) 王國堅決不向恐怖分子屈服
Our country has made the difficult decision
我國做出沉痛的決定
to carry out the operation to annihilate the Republic Gamma.
將正式執行剛瑪共和國殲滅作戰
This really is causing a public disturbance.
真是麻煩死了
PUBLIC OPINIONS ON THE GOVERNMENT I still find it very scary.
(民眾對於政府的看法) (20幾歲女性) 還是會覺得可怕
I hope this matter can be resolved soon.
(民眾對於政府的看法) (20幾歲女性) 能不能早點結束啊
By the way, what is the hero doing now?
話說勇者現在在幹嘛啊
Isn't the mastermind his companion?
罪魁禍首不就是他的夥伴嗎
A WOMAN IN HER 40S In the end, they caused the war.
(40幾歲女性) 到頭來戰爭都是他們挑起的
Shouldn't we hold that guy responsible?
不就該找那傢伙負責嗎
Why?
為什麼
Do you think I'm their father or something?
當我是他們老爸還是什麼嗎
This is nonsense.
有夠無聊
Mr. Max, where are you going?
麥克斯先生 你要去哪裡
I'm going for a walk.
散步
I'm going too.
朕也要去
If I leave him alone, he might bet 100 000 on horse racing this time.
不管他的話 這次搞不好會砸十萬賭賽馬
Bye.
慢走
Is there somewhere you would like to go
雖然說是散步
if you are going for a walk?
會不會想去哪裡走走
If I were to go alone, there would be a place I'd like to go.
若是我一人出來 倒是有地方想去
Then let's go there.
那就去那裡吧
You don't need to worry about me.
不必顧慮朕
I don't want to go.
鬼才要去
PRIVATE ROOM, MOVIE APPRECIATION What's with your tone?
(獨立包廂 影片鑑賞) 那是什麼語氣
Why won't you take me with you? Tell me!
為何不肯帶朕一起去 快說
PRIVATE ROOM, MOVIE APPRECIATION Shut up.
(獨立包廂 影片鑑賞) 吵死了
In any case, it's not a place to go with other person.
總之不適合跟別人去那裡
I am a demon's companion, not a person.
朕不是人 是魔之眷屬
Don't twist your words.
不要強詞奪理
No means no, whether you are a person or a demon clan.
管你是人類還是魔族 就是不行
Not a demon clan, you should say "demon's companion".
不是魔族 要講"魔之眷屬"才對
I don't care.
關我屁事
I found you. Is she your girlfriend?
找到了 她是你的女朋友嗎
I think I've seen you somewhere before.
朕好像在哪裡見過妳
Oh, you are the kid who was playing with Max the other day.
對了 是上次跟麥克斯玩的小孩
I apologize for constantly bothering you to accompany him.
真抱歉 總是麻煩妳陪他
Indecent woman.
猥褻女
What?
什麼
What are you talking about all of a sudden, you little brat?
妳這個小鬼頭突然胡說什麼
Where did you learn such words?
那種詞彙又是在哪裡學的
Your way of speaking is strange.
講話方式好怪
What are you holding?
妳拿的那是什麼
It's a badminton racket.
羽球拍
How are you going to play this alone?
妳一個人要怎麼玩
Yeah.
對啊
So I'm looking for someone to play with me. Will you play with me?
所以我正在找人 來陪我吧
You're so much trouble.
麻煩死了
Go find your friends.
去找妳的朋友啦
Isn't it good, Max?
豈不是挺好的嗎 麥克斯
It's healthier than gambling.
比賭博還要健康多了
SERGENDINE SECOND STREET PARK
(賽爾根達二丁目公園)
I lost again.
大叔又輸掉了耶
You're so good, little girl.
小妹妹妳好厲害喔
Your social skills are terrible, no wonder you can't get ahead.
應酬技巧這麼爛 難怪沒辦法出人頭地
She's so mean.
好嚴格
Is your mom doing well?
妳媽過得好嗎
Yes, although her stomach is super big.
嗯 雖然肚子超大的
My little brother is about to be born.
弟弟要出生了
Congratulations.
真是恭喜
Here you go.
給妳
Big sister, join us too.
大姐姐也加入吧
Do you want to play against me?
想跟朕對打嗎
Alright, but I won't go easy on you.
也行 但朕不會放水喔
No, no.
不是啦
You play against Max.
妳跟麥克斯對打
I'll watch.
我在旁邊看
That's alright for me…
是可以啊…
It would be problematic if she discovered your power.
萬一她發現你的力量 那就麻煩了
Just play around a little bit.
隨便打一打就好
Of course, I know.
朕當然知道
I'm going to serve.
要發球囉
Go.
去吧
Are you sure you want to maintain the status quo and do nothing?
確定要維持現狀 什麼都不做嗎
Your former companions are about to go to war.
你的昔日夥伴都要開戰了
You're quite a nagging fellow.
你也很囉唆耶
Saying we're companions, but that was ten years ago.
就算是夥伴 也是十年前的事了
It has nothing…
跟我…
to do with me.
毫無關係了
Leo and Fred might both die.
雷奧跟弗雷德說不定都會死
Even so,
即使如此
you still want to stay out of it?
還想置身事外嗎
What does it have to do with me?
關我什麼事
They brought it upon themselves.
這都是他們自找的
For me,
對我來說
the outcome of gambling is much more important.
賭博的輸贏重要多了
You would never say something
換作是十年前的你
like that ten years ago, would you?
絕對不會說那種話 不是嗎
Would you?
不是嗎…
Humans…
人類這種生物
can change drastically after ten years.
過了十年就會變得判若兩人
How could I always be a kid?
怎麼可能永遠當個小毛頭
You monsters probably wouldn't understand.
你們這些怪物大概不會懂吧
Bastard.
混蛋
Go to hell.
去死
Impressive.
好厲害
Worthy of the hero, I am a bit impressed.
不愧是勇者 有點刮目相看了
Well, thank you.
那真是謝了
"Play around a little bit"? Yet you take it so seriously.
什麼隨便打一打 結果打得那麼認真
Don't you take it seriously too?
你還不是一樣來真的
You think that's all I've got?
以為那就是朕的真本事嗎
It looks like you, as the hero, have also become a lot weaker.
看來你這個勇者也變弱了不少嘛
Shut up.
吵死了
Don't talk in my head, idiot.
不要在我的腦袋裡講話 笨蛋
What did you say?
你說什麼
By the way, I brought you a gift.
對了 我帶了禮物給你
Here.
拿去
A candy?
糖果
Yes, someone told me to give it to you.
對 有人叫我拿給你的
Big sister, can you teach me the move you just did?
大姐姐 教我剛才那招好不好
That was just a fluke.
那只是歪打正著啦
That damned woman.
那個臭女人…
What on earth does she want me to do?
到底…想要我怎麼做
Max, be careful.
麥克斯 小心
Captain Gelmof.
蓋爾莫夫大尉
We are ready to attack.
已做好進攻準備
Listen, Fred,
聽好了 弗雷德
you are not allowed to act on your own.
不准擅自行動
Let our attack army go first.
先由我軍攻擊部隊…
No need.
不必了
What?
什麼
Could the kingdom's army remain in place and keep the media and public at bay?
麻煩你們王國軍留在原地 阻止媒體與一般民眾進入
Are you joking?
開什麼玩笑
You're asking us to deal with the crowd?
你是叫我們去應付那些湊熱鬧的嗎
That's how we can avoid unnecessary casualties.
那樣才能避免無謂的傷亡
Don't underestimate us!
少瞧不起人了
You and Leo are the same.
你和雷奧都是一個樣
You never think about who caused all of this!
也不想想這一切是誰害的
Listen, I'm the commander of this operation.
聽好 這次作戰的指揮官是我
Shut up and follow my orders.
閉嘴聽我的命令就對了
You bunch of psychos.
你們這些神經病
You're making a lot of noise.
吵死了
I don't give a damn.
關我屁事
Wait, Chief, what are you doing?
等等 長官 您在做什麼
Doing this, you will…
做出這種事 您會…
I will most likely lose my position as chief.
長官的位子八成不保了
But that doesn't matter anymore.
不過那種事已經無所謂了
Let's end this, Leo.
做個了斷吧 雷奧
Former Chief.
前長官
What is it, former subordinate?
什麼事 前部下
You guys switched too quickly.
你們轉變得太快了吧
That city wall has a powerful defense spell.
那道城牆施加了強力的防衛魔法
The kingdom's magical weapons,
光靠王國的魔導兵器
didn't even leave a scratch on the wall.
甚至沒能造成半點傷害
Under these conditions, the fortress is still unresponsive.
在這種狀況下 要塞仍是毫無反應
What is the Republic planning?
共和國到底在打什麼主意
It seems unmanned.
看來無人駐守
Really?
真的嗎
They should know very well.
他們應該心知肚明
It's futile to keep guarding here.
繼續守在這裡也是徒勞無功
That's a wise judgement.
這是明智的判斷
Alright, this is my final order.
好了 這是我最後的命令
Don't let anyone pass through this ditch.
別讓任何人通過這道濠溝
I-I'm going too.
屬…屬下也去
Understood.
了解
You've worked hard all this time.
一直以來辛苦你們了
Chief.
長官…
Since he can fly, is there a need to destroy the city wall?
既然用飛的 那就不必破壞城牆吧
The wall separating
就在剛才
the Kingdom and the Republic
隨著猛烈的衝擊
was just destroyed by a powerful impact.
分隔王國與共和國的城牆遭到破壞
It appears that both sides have officially started the war.
似乎已經正式開戰
But currently, the traffic here is strictly controlled.
但是目前嚴格執行交通管制
The situation in the Republic…
共和國目前的狀況…
LIVE, BESKER KINGDOM'S BORDER There seems to be another explosion of light.
(現場轉播 貝斯卡王國國境) (快訊 國境一帶發生衝突與爆炸) 似乎又發生光之爆炸
BREAKING NEWS, FIGHTS AND EXPLOSIONS AT THE BORDER Is this the magic of Chief Fred?
(現場轉播 貝斯卡王國國境) (快訊 國境一帶發生衝突與爆炸) 不知是不是弗雷德長官的魔法
They have begun fighting.
開打了…
Making such a big scene
不愧是勇者夥伴
is typical of the hero's companions. Not bad.
搞得真誇張 不錯喔
Keep going, Fred.
好好加油吧 小弗雷德
As long as you win, it ends here. That would be the best.
只要你贏了 就此結束 那就再好不過了
Defeat Leo and the Republic will collapse.
打倒雷奧 共和國就會瓦解
But even if Fred loses, it doesn't matter.
但即使弗雷德輸了也無所謂
The "terror attacks launched by the Republic" will still continue.
"共和國發動的恐襲"仍會不斷發生
Tratigo's support for the Republic in order to obtain resources
多拉齊格為獲得資源而支援共和國
will most likely not be able to continue.
恐怕也無法繼續佯裝不知了吧
With Tratigo's withdrawal, the Republic will be on its own.
少了多拉齊格這個後盾 共和國將是孤立無援
Then, we just need to wait for them to starve and die.
再來只要等他們餓死就行了
Having said that,
話雖如此
if Fred dies,
萬一小弗雷德不幸死掉
I will be very lonely.
叔叔會很寂寞呢
Anyway, I'll just find another more flexible person to be the chief then.
反正到時找個 腦袋更靈活的傢伙當長官吧
Your Excellency.
閣下
There's a big problem.
大事不好了
What? What's wrong?
什麼 怎麼了
I thought I was on vacation today.
話說我今天不是休假嗎
There's no time for a vacation now, someone is live broadcasting.
現在哪有時間休假 有人在開實況轉播
When you say "broadcast", you mean what's on TV now.
妳說轉播 不就是電視的嗎
No, look here.
不是的 請看這邊
What is this? A live broadcast from PooCube?
這是什麼 PooCube的直播嗎
LIVE The Kingdom attacks Republic Gamma.
(實況轉播 王國進攻剛瑪共和國！直播中！) "王國進攻剛瑪共和國"
Live.
"實況轉播"
What is this?
這什麼東西
Why would anyone capture this?
為什麼有人拍得到這個
Wasn't the media blocked outside the wall?
媒體不是被擋在牆外嗎
Where are you looking, Fred?
你在看哪邊啊 弗雷德
Don't underestimate me.
別看扁我
Fred is so strong.
弗雷德好強
What is this? Which TV station captured it?
這是什麼 是哪家電視台拍的
Who knows, isn't it from your side?
誰知道 不是你那邊嗎
How do you watch this?
要怎麼看
Don't you use social media?
妳都沒在用社群網站嗎
Are you kidding me?
開什麼玩笑
Since the situation is live on TV, we cannot escape if something goes wrong.
即時轉播出去 萬一出狀況 就沒辦法找藉口脫身了
Quickly block the channel, shut it down.
快封鎖頻道 封掉它
No matter how many accounts we remove, new ones appear.
不管怎麼刪 還是越來越多
REINHARD
(萊因哈德)
Where is Gremes?
格雷姆斯在哪裡
Didn't he persuade Fred?
他不是說服弗雷德了嗎
If he talks too much, what should we do?
萬一他多嘴了 那該怎麼辦
Gremes, where on earth are you?
格雷姆斯 到底在哪裡
Gremes, was it your order?
格雷姆斯 是你下的指示嗎
No, what are you talking about?
不 你在說什麼
I just gave Fred a push for the sake of the kingdom.
我只是為了王國 推了弗雷德一把
I didn't expect it to be live broadcasted for the whole world to see.
沒想到會被別人直播給全世界看
Really?
真的嗎
Sometimes I don't understand what you're thinking, Gremes.
我偶爾會搞不懂 你究竟在想什麼 格雷姆斯
No matter how things develop, we need to settle this.
不管事情如何發展 都要做個了斷
The drone is filming, right?
無人機在拍吧
Currently, there's no problem.
目前沒問題
What about you?
妳那邊呢
I have prepared 7 700 disposable accounts.
我準備了7700個免洗帳號
It's useless no matter how you delete it.
怎麼刪除都沒用
Crossing Republic walls and trenches and sleeping in the wilderness was worth it.
翻牆越溝潛入 睡在荒郊野外都是值得的
I hope you can also consider those who are forced to accompany you.
能不能考慮一下 被迫陪妳的人的心情
Chief Fred obviously found the camera.
弗雷德長官顯然發現了攝影機
Honestly, I thought he would destroy it with magic right away.
坦白說我本來以為 他立刻就會用魔法破壞掉
Since he lets us be, that's pretty good, right?
既然他放任我們 那也挺好的啊
Is that okay?
不一定
After all, the kingdom would undoubtedly not want such footage to become public.
畢竟站在王國的角度 絕對不希望這種影像外流
Surely it's because he doesn't want to take care of the kingdom anymore.
肯定是因為他不想管王國了吧
Once, the hero and his group fought to keep the Kingdom safe.
勇者一行人 曾經為了守護王國而奮戰
But now they are at odds because of the kingdom's interests.
如今卻因為王國的利益而互相敵對
Fred probably can't take it anymore.
弗雷德恐怕也忍無可忍了
He intends to forego everything, including his status and reputation,
打算捨棄一切 包含地位與名譽
in order to engage in a deadly battle with his comrade Leo.
與戰友雷奧決一死戰
Isn't this…
這種事…
the kind of thing that everyone enjoys seeing?
不就是大家最愛看的嗎
I knew it.
我就知道
Come on, let's continue filming. We need to convey the truth.
來吧 繼續拍下去 將真相傳達出去
Okay.
好喔
It hurts.
好痛
Here you are.
你來啦
What's with your disgustingly long hair?
你那頭噁心的長髮是怎樣
Who are you trying to seduce?
是在發情嗎
Don't you think about how old you are?
也不想一下你幾歲了
My subordinates seem to have caused you trouble.
我的部下好像給你添麻煩了
You're taking it too easy with your feelings.
講得這麼悠哉 沒問題嗎
Don't you worry about their safety?
都不會擔心他們的安危嗎
I am just worried that if they lie down on the ground, mosquitos will bite them.
我只怕他們躺在地上 會不會被蚊子叮
I've told them not to bother.
虧我叫他們不要攪局
I apologize.
抱歉
Then you should wait for me near the city wall.
那你不能在離城牆更近的地方等嗎
By the way, have you seen Max recently?
對了 你最近有沒有跟麥克斯見面
Have you seen him?
你見到他了嗎
Yeah, it startled me.
對啊 害我大吃一驚
Is that bastard serious?
那個混蛋真的跑來了
I'm going to kill him.
我要殺了他
I didn't recognize him at first because he was wearing glasses.
我一開始沒認出來 因為他戴眼鏡
But his skills have not regressed at all.
不過戰鬥身手絲毫沒退步
What about that thing flying in the sky?
飛在天上的那東西怎麼辦
If you don't want to be filmed, then do it as you like.
如果不方便被拍到 那就隨你處置
Then I'll make it easier to film.
乾脆讓它拍得更清楚一點
Is this okay?
這樣就行了吧
No, since we have the chance, let's be a little more considerate.
不 機會難得 不如再貼心一點
These two are outrageous. Is the drone okay?
太離譜了吧 無人機沒事嗎
I guess so.
算是吧
Is this for real?
真的假的
It's not bad like this.
還不錯吧
The view is quite good.
景色挺好的
Goodbye, Fred.
永別了 弗雷德
This wand will serve as your tombstone, Leo.
這法杖就當你的墓碑吧 雷奧
Leo, Fred, how did it come to this?
雷奧 弗雷德 怎麼會變成這樣